A Finding Aid to the Peter Howard Selz papers, 1929-2014, bulk 1950-2005, in the Archives of American Art AAA.selzpete
Archives of American Art
- Artists' Research Files, 1955-2014; Series 6; 7.9 Linear feet Box 15-22, OV 34-35
  - Hadzi, Dmitri (Box 18)
    - Interview Transcript, 1981-1985 (Box 18, Folder 24-25)
    - Biographical Material and Notes, circa 1995 (Box 18, Folder 26)
    - "Dimitri Hadzi: Sculpture in the Public Domain" Drafts, 1995-1996 (Box 18, Folder 27)
    - "Dimitri Hadzi at 85" Drafts, 2003-2006 (Box 18, Folder 28)
  - Hammons, David, 2000-2003 (Box 18, Folder 29)
  - Hartley, Marsden, circa 1978 (Box 18, Folder 30)
  - Hasson, Bruce, 1989-2003 (Box 18, Folder 31)
  - Hedrick, Wally, 1994-2004 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Hefferton, Phillip, 2004 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Heizer, Michael, 1980-1981 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Helnwein, Gottfried, 1996-2002 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Herman, Roger, 1980-1983 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Hershman, Lynn, 2003-2005 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Hibi, Matsusaburo, circa 2000 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Hiramoto, Judy, 1999-2002 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Hodler, Ferdinand, 1973-1978 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Hofmann, Hans, 1992 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Howard, Mildred, circa 2000 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Huelga, 2002 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Ikemoto, Howard, 1996-2003 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Ireland, David, 2003-2004 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Jess, 2003-2007 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Jones, John Paul, 2003-2010 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Kadishman, Menashe, 1970-1980 (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Kahn, Herbert, circa 1998 (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Kahn, Tobi, 1978-2005 (Box 19, Folder 19-21)
  - Kala Art Institute, circa 1990 (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - Kamler, Richard Dean, 2000-2006 (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - Kelley, Mike, 2002-2004 (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - Kepes, Gyorgy, 1985 (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - Kienholz, Ed, 1999-2001 (Box 19, Folder 26)
  - Kilgallen, Margaret, 2004 (Box 19, Folder 27)
  - King, Tony, 1995-1997 (Box 19, Folder 28)
  - Koci, Frank, 2008-2009 (Box 19, Folder 29)
  - Komisar, Milton, 1979-1981 (Box 19, Folder 30)
    Oversized material housed in OV 35.
  - Kostka, Robert, 1991-2006 (Box 19, Folder 31)
  - Kricke, Norbert, 1977-1984 (Box 19, Folder 32)
  - Kruger, Barbara, 2004 (Box 19, Folder 33)
  - Lacy, Suzanne, 2003 (Box 19, Folder 34)
  - LaMarr, Jean, 2003 (Box 19, Folder 35)
  - Lane, Christopher (Box 19)
    - Typescript Draft of Exhibition Review, 1982 (Box 19, Folder 36)
    - Biographical Material and Resume, circa 1982 (Box 19, Folder 37)
    - Correspondence and Printed Material, 1982-1985 (Box 19, Folder 38)
  - LaPena, Frank, 1999-2004 (Box 19, Folder 39)
  - Le, Dinh Q., 2003 (Box 19, Folder 40)
  - Lebrun, Rico - Correspondence, 1957-1993 (Box 19, Folder 41-43)
  - Lebrun, Rico (Box 20)
    - Correspondence, 1994-2001 (Box 20, Folder 1-2)
    - Archives of American Art Correspondence, 1976-1977 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Writings and Notes, circa 1976 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - "The Genesis of Genesis" Drafts, circa 1976 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, 1963-1964 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Photographs of Artwork, circa 1960-circa 1976 (Box 20, Folder 7-8)
    - News Clippings, 1961 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Printed Material, 1960-1964 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Liu, Hung, 2000-2004 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Lobdell, Frank, 2002 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Longfish, George, 2003-2004 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Luna, James, 2003-2005 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Maisel, David, 2003-2005 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Manzu, Giacomo, 2000-2002 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Matthews, Susan, 2003-2009 (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - McCormick, Daniel, 2002-2003 (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - McCoy, Ann, 1985-1986 (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - McGee, Barry, 2000-2004 (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - McLaughlin, Jerry, 1989-1997 (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - McLeod, Scott, 2002 (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - Mesa-Bains, Amalia, 2002 (Box 20, Folder 23)
  - Mesches, Arnold, 1982-2012 (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - Milder, Jay, 1987-2011 (Box 20, Folder 25-26)
  - Milder, Jay - Photographic Material, 2011 (Box 20, Folder 27)
  - Min, Yong Soon, 2004 (Box 20, Folder 28)
  - Misrach, Richard, 2003 (Box 20, Folder 29)
  - Modersohn-Becker, Paula, 2007-2008 (Box 20, Folder 30)
  - Montano, Linda, 2003 (Box 20, Folder 31)
  - Montoya, Malaquias, 2003-2005 (Box 20, Folder 32)
  - Nagel, Andres, 1992-1997 (Box 20, Folder 33)
  - Namuth, Hans - Interview Transcript, 1971 (Box 20, Folder 34)
  - Namuth, Hans - Printed Material, 1977-1984 (Box 20, Folder 35)
  - Nolde, Emil, 1963-1982 (Box 20, Folder 36)
  - Norman, Irving, 2001 (Box 20, Folder 37)
  - Ocampo, Manuel, 1994-2006 (Box 20, Folder 38)
  - Onslow Ford, Gordon, 1992-1993 (Box 20, Folder 39)
  - Opie, Catherine, 2004 (Box 20, Folder 40)
  - Ox, Jack, 1994 (Box 20, Folder 41)
  - Paris, Harold (Box 21)
    - Notes and Printed Material, circa 1970-circa 1990 (Box 21, Folder 1-2)
    - Lecture Drafts, circa 1972 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Biographical Material, circa 1972-circa 1990 (Box 21, Folder 4-5)
    - Michael Smith Gallery Consignment Agreements and Correspondence, 1972-1974 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Probate of Harold Paris Legal Papers and Correspondence, 1979-1986 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence about Additions to H. Paris Collection, 1990-1991 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - General Correspondence, 1993-2004 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Parker, Gertrud, 2006 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Partenheimer, Jurgen, 1983-1987 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Perez, Francisco, 2000-2003 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Petlin, Irving (Box 21)
    - Irving Petlin Correspondence, 2008-2009 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts Correspondence, 2005-2006 (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - General Correspondence, 2000-2008 (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Interview Transcripts, 2005; Includes 1 cassette tape. (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - Untitled Essay Draft, circa 2000 (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - "Endgame" Exhibition Essay Draft, 2002 (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - Art in America Essay Drafts, 2009; Includes 1 sound disc (CD) with images. (Box 21, Folder 19)
    - Retrospective Essay Drafts, circa 2010 (Box 21, Folder 20)
    - Photocopies of Artwork Images, circa 2009 (Box 21, Folder 21)
    - Photographs and Slides of Artwork, 2009 (Box 21, Folder 22)
      Oversized photograph housed in OV 34.
    - Printed Material, 1981-2008 (Box 21, Folder 23)
  - Pham, Hanh Thi, 2004 (Box 21, Folder 24)
  - Pittman, Lari, 2003 (Box 21, Folder 25)
  - Purifoy, Noah, 2005 (Box 21, Folder 26)
  - Rascon, Armando, 1994-2003 (Box 21, Folder 27)
  - Register, John, 1998 (Box 21, Folder 28)
  - Rigo, circa 2000 (Box 21, Folder 29)
  - Ringgold, Faith, 2001-2004 (Box 21, Folder 30)
  - Ritchey, Rik, 1986-1989 (Box 21, Folder 31)
  - Rodia, Simon, 1979 (Box 21, Folder 32)
  - Romero, Frank, 2002 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Rosen, James Mahlon, 1990-1995 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Rosenthal, Rachel, 2003; Includes 1 sound disc (CD). (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Rosler, Martha, 2000-2005 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Rothenberg, Erika, 1999-2005 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Rubins, Nancy, 2003 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Saar, Alison, circa 2000 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Saar, Betye, 2002-2003 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Sakoguchi, Ben, circa 2003 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Sances, Jos, 1990-2002 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Saul, Peter, 1999-2004 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Saunders, Raymond, 1999 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Schöffer, Nicolas, 1983-1984 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Schneemann, Carolee, 1984-1991 (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Sekula, Allan, 2003 (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Shawcroft, Barbara, 1976-1987 (Box 22, Folder 16-17)
  - Sherk, Bonnie, 2003 (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - Snowden, Mary, 1995-2004 (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - Somerville, Travis, 1999-2003 (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - Spence, Kathryn, 2004 (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - Stanley, M. Louise, 2000-2004 (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - Steichen, Edward, 1988 (Box 22, Folder 23)
  - Stettheimer, Florine, circa 1975 (Box 22, Folder 24)
  - Still, Clyfford, 1975 (Box 22, Folder 25)
  - Stuppin, Jack, 2008-2009 (Box 22, Folder 26)
  - Takis, 1977-1984 (Box 22, Folder 27)
  - Teraoka, Masami, 1989-2003 (Box 22, Folder 28)
  - Thompson, Mark, 2004 (Box 22, Folder 29)
  - Tinguely, Jean, 1960-1977 (Box 22, Folder 30)
  - Torres, Salvador Roberto, 2002-2004 (Box 22, Folder 31)
  - Underwood, Consuelo Jimenez, 1990-2002 (Box 22, Folder 32)
  - Valdez, Patssi, 1999-2001 (Box 22, Folder 33)
  - Varlin (Willy Guggenheim), 1985-1986 (Box 22, Folder 34)
  - Vavagiakis, Costa, 2000 (Box 22, Folder 35)
  - Vedova, Emilio, 1983-1995 (Box 22, Folder 36)
  - Vignes, Michelle, 2002 (Box 22, Folder 37)
  - Villa, Carlos, 2004-2005; Includes 4 sound discs (CDs). (Box 22, Folder 38-40)
  - Wade, Kat, 2003 (Box 22, Folder 41)
  - Waldman, Selma, 2006-2008; Includes 1 sound disc (CD). (Box 22, Folder 42)
  - Wall, Brian, 1982 (Box 22, Folder 43)
  - White, Charles, 2001-2002 (Box 22, Folder 44)
  - Wilding, Faith, 2003 (Box 22, Folder 45)
  - Wiley, William T., 2003-2005 (Box 22, Folder 46)
  - Yeager, Ira, 2007 (Box 22, Folder 47)
  - Oversized Max Beckmann Clippings from Box 15, Folder 35, 1964-1965 (Box OV 34)
  - Oversized Irving Petlin Artwork Photograph from Box 21, Folder 22 (Box OV 34)
  - Oversized Milton Komisar Material from Box 19, Folder 30, 1979-1981 (Box OV 35)
- Exhibition Files, 1960-2012; Series 7; 5 Linear feet Box 23-27
  Exhibition files are found for numerous exhibitions organized by Selz, or to which he contributed. Files may include exhibition catalogs, reviews, clippings, writings, correspondence, and other material. Files are found for Seven Decades of Modern Art, 1895-1965 (1965), The Joint Show (1967), The American Presidency in Political Cartoons (1976), American Modern Art Between the Two World Wars (1979), German Realism in the Twenties: Artist As Social Critic (1980), Twelve Artists from the German Democratic Republic (1989), Sam Francis: Blue Balls (1991), a Richard Lindner Retrospective (1996), Spaces of Nature (1999), and a Nathan Oliviera Retrospective (2002), among many others. There are 4 CDs.
  Exhibitions are arranged by title in chronological order, and further by document type if needed.
  - Museum of Modern Art, Art Nouveau Exhibition (1960) (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - "Fifteen Polish Painters" (1961), 1960-1961 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Battersea Park Open Air Exhibition (1963), circa 1963 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Documenta III Exhibition (1964), 1963-1964 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - "Seven Decades of Modern Art, 1895-1965" (1965) (Box 23)
    - Correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 23, Folder 5-6)
    - Undated Correspondence, circa 1965 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Meeting Minutes and Loan Forms, 1965-1966 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Kinetic Sculpture Exhibition (1966) (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - "The Joint Show" (1967) (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Exhibition Announcements, 1967 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Photographs, 1967 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Printed Material, 1967 (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - "The Hippie Poster" Drafts, 1967 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - "The American Presidency in Political Cartoons, 1776-1976" (1976) (Box 23)
    - Correspondence, 1973-1978 (Box 23, Folder 14-16)
    - Notes, circa 1975 (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - Exhibition Outline and Planning, circa 1976 (Box 23, Folder 18)
    - Exhibition Checklists, circa 1976 (Box 23, Folder 19)
    - Catalog Outline and Draft, circa 1976 (Box 23, Folder 20)
    - Photographic Material, 1976 (Box 23, Folder 21)
    - Printed Material, 1975-1976 (Box 23, Folder 22)
    - Exhibition Reviews, 1976 (Box 23, Folder 23)
  - "Art in a Turbulent Era: German and Austrian Expressionism" (1978) - Correspondence, 1976-1978 (Box 23, Folder 24-25)
  - "American Modern Art Between the Two World Wars" (1979) (Box 23)
    - Dore Ashton Correspondence, 1978 (Box 23, Folder 26)
    - Nan Rosenthal Correspondence, 1976-1978 (Box 23, Folder 27)
    - Stadtische Kunsthalle Dusseldorf Correspondence, 1977-1980 (Box 23, Folder 28)
    - Correspondence with Lenders, A-Z, 1976-1979 (Box 23, Folder 29-34)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1977-1979 (Box 23, Folder 35)
    - Loan Forms, A-F, 1978 (Box 23, Folder 36)
    - Loan Forms, G-N, 1978 (Box 23, Folder 37)
    - Loan Forms, O-Z, 1978 (Box 23, Folder 38)
    - Financial Records, 1978 (Box 23, Folder 39)
    - Exhibition Checklists, circa 1978 (Box 23, Folder 40)
  - "American Modern Art Between the Two World Wars" (1979) (Box 24)
    - Notes and Early Catalog Draft, 1978 (Box 24, Folder 1-2)
    - Exhibition Catalog Draft, circa 1978 (Box 24, Folder 3-4)
    - Printed Material, 1979 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - "German Realism in the Twenties: The Artist as Social Critic" (1980) (Box 24)
    - Correspondence, 1978-1981 (Box 24, Folder 6-7)
    - Notes for Exhibition Catalog, circa 1979 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Notes on Neue Sachlichkeit, circa 1979 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Loan Lists, 1979-1980 (Box 24, Folder 10-11)
  - "The Art Fabric: Mainstream" (1981) (Box 24)
    - Correspondence, 1981 (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Press Releases, 1981 (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Notes, 1981 (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - "Fabricart" Essay Drafts, 1981 (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - "Kandinsky in Munich" (1982), 1981-1982 (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - Michael Dvortcsak Exhibition (circa 1983) (Box 24)
    - Correspondence, 1983-1985 (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - Writings, circa 1983 (Box 24, Folder 18)
    - Printed Material and Slides, 1983-1985 (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - Jose Luis Cuevas Retrospective (1984), 1983-1984 (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - "Italian Art of the Twentieth Century" (circa 1984), 1981-1984 (Box 24, Folder 21)
  - Rupert Garcia (1985) (Box 24, Folder 22)
  - Alain Gerbault: Vertical Chamber: 115 Feet High (1986) (Box 24, Folder 23)
  - Santa Barbara Contemporary Arts Forum Exhibition (1987), 1985-1986 (Box 24, Folder 24)
  - "It's Possible: 24 Israeli & Palestinian Artists Unite for Peace" (1989), 1988-1989 (Box 24, Folder 25)
  - "12 Artists from the German Democratic Republic" (1989) (Box 24)
    - General Correspondence, 1984-1989 (Box 24, Folder 26)
    - Harvard University Art Museums Correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 24, Folder 27)
    - Artists Biographical Information, circa 1989 (Box 24, Folder 28)
    - Notes, circa 1989 (Box 24, Folder 29)
    - Printed Material, 1989-1990 (Box 24, Folder 30)
  - "Sam Francis: Blue Balls" (1991) (Box 25)
    - Correspondence, 1990-1995 (Box 25, Folder 1-2)
    - Notes, circa 1991 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Exhibition Catalog Drafts and Images, circa 1991 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Photographs, 1960-1965 (Box 25, Folder 5)
      Includes black and white photographs of the artist and some art inside a studio.
  - "Degenerate Art" (1993), 1992-1993 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - "Explorations in the City of Light: African-American Artists in Paris, 1945-1965" (1996), 1993-1996 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Hirshhorn Museum, Richard Lindner Retrospective (1996) (Box 25)
    - Judith Zilczer Correspondence, 1994-1996 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence about Chronology for Biography, 1995 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - General Correspondence, 1993-1996 (Box 25, Folder 10-11)
    - Inventories of Paintings, circa 1993 (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Project Outline, circa 1994 (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - Printed Material and Interview Transcripts, circa 1994 (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - Notes for Essay, circa 1994 (Box 25, Folder 15)
    - January 1995 Essay Draft (Box 25, Folder 16)
    - February 1995 Essay Draft (Box 25, Folder 17)
    - June 1995 Essay Draft (Box 25, Folder 18)
    - "Richard Lindner's Armored Woman" Final Drafts, circa 1996 (Box 25, Folder 19)
    - Essay Draft by Judith Zilczer, circa 1994 (Box 25, Folder 20)
    - Miscellaneous Printed Material, 1969-1978 (Box 25, Folder 21)
  - "Offshore: Paintings of the Farallones" (1997) (Box 25, Folder 22)
  - Havana Bienal Art Festival (1999), 1988-2000 (Box 25, Folder 23)
  - Valpraisio University, Robert Kostka and Stephen De Staebler Exhibitions (1999), 1996-1999 (Box 25, Folder 24)
  - "Spaces of Nature" (1999) (Box 25)
    - Planning, Checklists, and Exhibition Agreement, 1998-1999 (Box 25, Folder 25)
    - Bellaver, Tony, 1998-1999 (Box 25, Folder 26)
  - "Spaces of Nature" (1999) (Box 26)
    - Brest van Kempen, Mark, 1998-1999 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Champion, Alex, 1998-1999 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Chanco, Pauletta M., 1998-1999 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Hofmann, Angelika, 1998-1999 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Mark, Sue, 1998-1999 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - McCormick, Daniel, 1998-1999 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Nelson, Keiko, 1998-1999 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Polster, Laurie, 1998-1999 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Exhibition Catalog, 1999 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - "Modern Odysseys: Greek American Artists of the 20th Century" (2000) (Box 26)
    - Thalia Selz Correspondence, 1992-1998 (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Bill Valerio Correspondence, 1999 (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Queens Museum of Art Correspondence, 1997-1999 (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence with Artists, 1998-1999 (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - Exhibition Planning and Agreement, 1996-1998 (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - Checklists, 1999-2000 (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - "Color and Fire: Defining Moments in Studio Ceramics, 1950-2000" (2000) (Box 26)
    - Los Angeles County Museum of Art Correspondence, 1998-2000 (Box 26, Folder 16-17)
    - "The Figurative Impulse in Ceramics" Essay Drafts, circa 1999 (Box 26, Folder 18)
    - Images of Artwork from Participating Artists, 1999 (Box 26, Folder 19)
    - Araki, Takako, 1999-2000 (Box 26, Folder 20)
    - Beere, Susan, 1999 (Box 26, Folder 21)
    - Carhartt, Elaine, 1999-2000 (Box 26, Folder 22)
    - Cecula, Marek, 1999-2000 (Box 26, Folder 23)
    - De Staebler, Stephen, 1999-2000 (Box 26, Folder 24)
    - Frimkess, Michael, 1999-2000 (Box 26, Folder 25)
    - Green, Phyllis, 1999-2000 (Box 26, Folder 26)
    - Levine, Marilyn, 1999-2000 (Box 26, Folder 27)
    - Lucero, Michael, 1999-2000 (Box 26, Folder 28)
    - Notkin, Richard, 1999-2000 (Box 26, Folder 29)
    - Shaw, Richard and Robert Hudson, 1999-2000 (Box 26, Folder 30)
    - Takamori, Akio, 1993-2000 (Box 26, Folder 31)
    - VandenBerge, Peter, 1999-2000 (Box 26, Folder 32)
    - Voulkos, Peter, 1999-2000 (Box 26, Folder 33)
  - "Cross-Currents in Modern Art: A Tribute to Peter Selz" (2000) (Box 26)
    - Achim Moeller Gallery Correspondence, 1998-2000 (Box 26, Folder 34)
    - General Correspondence, 1999 (Box 26, Folder 35)
    - Peter Selz Interview Transcripts, 1999-2000 (Box 26, Folder 36)
    - Typescript Drafts and Printed Material, 1999-2000 (Box 26, Folder 37)
    - Exhibition Checklists and Publicity, 2000-2001 (Box 26, Folder 38)
  - Nathan Oliviera Retrospective and Monograph (2002) (Box 26)
    - Exhibition Planning Correspondence, 1998-2001 (Box 26, Folder 39)
    - John Berggruen Gallery Correspondence, 2001 (Box 26, Folder 40)
    - Photocopies of Nathan Oliviera's Correspondence with Galleries, 1957-1977 (Box 26, Folder 41)
    - Nathan Oliviera Correspondence, 1999-2000 (Box 26, Folder 42)
  - Nathan Oliviera Retrospective and Monograph (2002) (Box 27)
    - Palm Springs Desert Museum Correspondence, 2002-2003 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Portugal Embassy Correspondence, 1999-2000 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - San Jose Museum of Art Correspondence, 2000 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - San Jose Museum of Art Correspondence and Checklists, 2001-2002 (Box 27, Folder 4-5)
    - University of California Press Correspondence, 2000 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Exhibition Proposal and Agreement, 1999-2000 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Art Loan Requests, 2002 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Reviews, 2002 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Nathan Oliviera Interview Transcripts, 1978-2000 (Box 27, Folder 10-12)
    - Typescript Drafts of Introduction by Joann Moser, 1999-2000 (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Typescript Drafts of Biography, circa 2002 (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - Bibliography, 1999 (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - Printed Material and Notes, 1952-1989 (Box 27, Folder 16-19)
    - Hirsshorn Museum Records on Nathan Oliviera's Artwork, circa 1999 (Box 27, Folder 20)
    - Photographs of Artwork, circa 1999 (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - Lyonel Feininger Watercolors Exhibition (2003), 2002-2003 (Box 27, Folder 22)
  - "Trans: Abstraction" (2007), 2007-2009; Includes 2 sound discs (CD). (Box 27, Folder 23)
  - "Gustav Klimt: In Search of the 'Total Artwork'" (2009), 2007-2008 (Box 27, Folder 24)
  - George Krevsky Gallery, Richard Lindner Exhibition (2009), 2008-2009 (Box 27, Folder 25)
  - Dolby Chadwick Gallery, "Heads" (2011), 2010-2011 (Box 27, Folder 26)
  - "Framing Abstraction: Mark, Symbol, Signifier" (2011), circa 2011 (Box 27, Folder 27)
  - "Eco-Art on Paper" (2011), 2010-2011; Includes 2 sound discs (CD). (Box 27, Folder 28)
  - "The Painted Word" (2012) (Box 27, Folder 29)
- Personal Business Records, 1929-2011; Series 8; 1.1 Linear feet Box 28-29, OV 36
  The bulk of the personal business records are related to the “Matter of Rothko,” Kate Rothko’s legal case against Marlborough Gallery, Inc. Also included in this series are assorted personal documents such as Peter Selz’s school transcripts, designs for his Regal Street home in California, bequests, royalty statements, and estate papers for a relative.
  - "Matter of Rothko" Lawsuit (Box 28)
    - Transcript of Peter Selz Testimony, 1974 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Transcript of Spencer A. Samuels Testimony, 1974 (Box 28, Folder 2-3)
    - Transcript of Peter Selz Testimony, 1974 (Box 28, Folder 4-5)
    - Lawrence Fleischman and Klaus Perls Depositions, 1974 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Notes, circa 1974 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1974-1977 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Appraisals B1.70-1312.69, 1970-1972 (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Appraisals 5003.63-6020.23, 1970-1972 (Box 28, Folder 10-12)
    - 861 Regal Road Property, 1964-1994 (Box 28, Folder 26-29)
      Oversized material housed in OV 36.
    - "Comparison of Heller's Evaluations and Actual Sales of Paintings", circa 1974 (Box 28, Folder 13-15)
    - Price List for Paintings in European Traveling Retrospective, 1971-1972 (Box 28, Folder 16)
    - Sales List of Rothko Paintings, 1974 (Box 28, Folder 17)
    - Sales List of Rothko "Paper in Order of Size", 1974 (Box 28, Folder 18)
    - Sales List of Oils on Canvas, circa 1974 (Box 28, Folder 19)
    - "Mark Rothko: Ten Major Works" Exhibition Catalog, 1974 (Box 28, Folder 20)
    - Photocopy of German Rothko Exhibition Catalog, 1974 (Box 28, Folder 21)
    - Clippings, 1961-1978 (Box 28, Folder 22-23)
    - Oliver Wick Correspondence, 2000-2008 (Box 28, Folder 24)
  - Peter Selz School Transcripts, 1929-1939 (Box 28, Folder 25)
  - Art Library Bequest to M. H. de Young Museum, 1996-2001 (Box 28, Folder 30)
  - Art Institute of Chicago Bequests, 1996 (Box 28, Folder 31)
  - Estate of Paul H. Weil, 2002-2005 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - University of California Press Royalty Statements, 2002-2011 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Oversized Regal Road Plans from Box 28, Folder 26, circa 1966 (Box OV 36)
- Printed Material, 1957-2004; Series 9; 0.3 Linear feet Box 29
  Printed materials include copies of articles written by Peter Selz, images of artwork, news clippings, and miscellaneous materials.
  - Articles by Peter Selz, 1957-1962 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Articles by Peter Selz, 1963-1973 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - News Clippings, 1961 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Photocopies of Images of Artwork, circa 1984 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material, 2001-2004 (Box 29, Folder 7)
- Scrapbooks, 1947-2012; Series 10; 1.3 Linear feet Box 29-31
  Scrapbooks consists of 9 disbound binders which date from the late 1940s up through 2012. The binders contain newspaper clippings, exhibition announcements, and photographs of events at galleries and museums. There are numerous photographs of Selz and various artists. The titles in quotation marks were taken from the original labels on the binders.
  The binders are arranged chronologically.
  - Binder 1: 1940s and 1950s, 1947-1959 (Box 29, Folder 8-9)